<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wxPython (Posts about Life)</title><link>https://wxpython.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://wxpython.org/categories/life.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:robin@alldunn.com"&gt;The wxPython Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 03:07:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Horizons</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past few months I have been working for
&lt;a href="http://enthought.com"&gt;Enthought&lt;/a&gt; and helping out with a new upcoming
product. Since that is about to transition to a more long term
employment opportunity for me I figured it would be a good idea to let
the &lt;a href="http://wxPython.org"&gt;wxPython&lt;/a&gt; community know about it, and also to
let you know about some aspects of the job that some may find a little
surprising, before you hear about it as rumors or gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Software</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We'll miss you Neil</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/well-miss-you-neil/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Neil Armstrong" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2012/08/neil_armstrong.jpeg" title="Neil Armstrong"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neil Armstrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll miss you Neil.  Breathe free.  Fly high.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/well-miss-you-neil/index.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 10:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>OS X Lion Was My Idea</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/os-x-lion-was-my-idea/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several months ago Microsoft had an ad campaign where they would have an
average Joe or Jane talk about some cool wizbang feature of Windows 7
and how it was all their idea.  It was one of Microsoft's better ad
campaigns, and was actually understandable by the average person without
requiring the viewer to know industry inside jokes, or to understand
Jerry Seinfeld, to be able to "get" the gist of the commercial.  It also
employed some cute gimmicks, such as when the person was remembering
back to how they thought up the wonderful new idea the directors used a
different actor who was younger, thinner, cuter, handsomer, and had way
better hair than the real person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/blog/os-x-lion-was-my-idea/index.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Mac</category><category>Software</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/os-x-lion-was-my-idea/index.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 16:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Happy Towel Day!</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/happy-towel-day/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Do you know where your &lt;a href="http://www.towelday.org/"&gt;towel&lt;/a&gt; is?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Life</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/happy-towel-day/index.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 14:08:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In memory of Laddie</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/in-memory-of-laddie/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My dog Laddie" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2010/05/Laddie-2-767x1024.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tribute to a Dog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best friend a man has in the world may turn against him and become
his enemy. His son or daughter that he has reared with loving care may
prove ungrateful. Those who are nearest and dearest to us, those whom we
trust with our happiness and our good name may become traitors to their
faith. The money that a man has, he may lose. It flies away from him,
perhaps when he needs it most. A man's reputation may be sacrificed in a
moment of ill-considered action. The people who are prone to fall on
their knees to do us honor when success is with us, may be the first
tothrow the stone of malice when failure settles its cloud upon our
heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one absolutely unselfish friend that man can have in this selfish
world, the one that never deserts him, the one that never proves
ungrateful or treacherous, is his dog. A man's dog stands by him in
prosperity and in poverty, in health and in sickness. He will sleep on
the cold ground, where the wintry winds blow and the snow drives
fiercely, if only he may be near his master's side. He will kiss the
hand that has no food to offer. He will lick the wounds and sores that
come in encounters with the roughness of the world. He guards the sleep
of his pauper master as if he were a prince. When all other friends
desert, he remains. When riches take wings, and reputation falls to
pieces, he is as constant in his love as the sun in its journey through
the heavens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If fortune drives the master forth, an outcast in the world, friendless
and homeless, the faithful dog asks no higher privilege than that of
accompanying him, to guard him against danger, to fight against his
enemies. And when the last scene of all comes, and death takes his
master in its embrace and his body is laid away in the cold ground, no
matter if all other friends pursue their way, there by the graveside
will the noble dog be found, his head between his paws, his eyes sad,
but open in alert watchfulness, faithful and true even in death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;George Graham Vest, 1870&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/in-memory-of-laddie/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2010 11:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tweet, Tweet!</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/tweet-tweet/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A number of people have asked me about it and so I finally decided that
it is high time that I give the whole &lt;a href="http://twitter.com"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;
thing a try.  Of course I've gotten into it late enough that my usual
user name, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/RobinD"&gt;RobinD&lt;/a&gt; is already taken,
although that page returns an error.  (I suspect that somebody got their
account suspended...)  Strangely enough somebody has already registered
the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/wxPython"&gt;wxPython&lt;/a&gt; name, although they haven't
tweeted anything since last July...  Anyway, if you'd like to follow me
or send me messages on twitter I am known there as
&lt;a href="http://twitter.com/RobinD42"&gt;RobinD42&lt;/a&gt;. Bear with me while I take my
first steps in this new environment...&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Life</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/tweet-tweet/index.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2009 15:47:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time Machine Saves Bacon</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/time-machine-saves-bacon/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I know what you're thinking... That headline sounds like something
you might read while standing in the checkout line at the supermarket
next to photos of aliens from the future rescuing some baby porkers from
the path of a Vogon engineered tornado headed for the next trailer park
on their list of sites to demolish to make room for a new highway. Well
if that's what you're thinking (come on, admit it, you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; you were)
then you're wrong. Keep reading for some info about another kind of Time
Machine, and another kind of Bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/blog/time-machine-saves-bacon/index.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Mac</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/time-machine-saves-bacon/index.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 20:10:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Tranquility base here, the Robin has landed..."</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/tranquility-base-here-the-robin-has-landed/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Since a number of folks have expressed interest and concern I thought I
would give a quick update on my working situation. This week I've
started a full-time consulting job with a small software group at the
&lt;a href="http://unmc.edu"&gt;University of Nebraska Medical Center&lt;/a&gt;. If you
attended &lt;a href="http://pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; a couple years ago then you may have
seen their
&lt;a href="http://us.pycon.org/zope/talks/2006/sun/track1/37/talkDetails"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;
about IntúaCare and IntúaDesign. That is the project that I'll be
working with. I'll be working &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; wxPython a lot, and probably also
working &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; wxWidgets and wxPython to some extent as well, although not
as much as I did with OSAF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to be working on this project. Not just because of wxPython,
but also because I have previous experience with the subject matter. My
first major job out of college was working on software products that had
a lot of the same goals as the IntúaSolutions products: essentially to
be a highly dynamic and flexible solution for collecting and reporting
medical patient care data in hospitals. The key here is the "highly
dynamic and flexible" part, the intent is to have a set of
domain-specific tools where unskilled (a.k.a non-programmers) but
knowledgeable people can easily tailor the application to the needs of
each hospital, or even each department within the hospital. My former
experience with this was back in the dark days of DOS so the products
had only a textual user interface, but I think we managed to accomplish
a lot with it and it was a very successful product line, and at least as
of a few years ago it was still going strong, although they've
modernized a bunch of things since I worked there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously a few things have changed in the computer world since then. I
discovered Python a year or so after I left that job and I've always
wondered what it would have been like if we had used Python as the
internal macro/calculation/filtering/query language instead of our
home-grown RDL (for anyone outside of the marketing group and the
customers that acronym stands for Robin Dunn's Language, otherwise it is
Rule Definition Language.) Since that time we've also gone through the
rise of the graphical user interface, the explosion of the World Wide
Web, and my current notebook computer has 7.5 times the number of pixels
on screen and 8 times more RAM than the hard drive space in the brand
new top of the line desktop computer I had when we started that project!
It should be fun to be able to apply modern technology and my new skills
to similar features and issues that I dealt with 14-18 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've linked to this video as a way to let you know how big of an effort
this job search seemed to be at times, and also how good it felt when it
was finally complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;object height="355" width="425"&gt;
&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/xLu0Ak9Blog&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="transparent"&gt;

&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/xLu0Ak9Blog&amp;amp;hl=en" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" height="355" width="425"&gt;
&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/tranquility-base-here-the-robin-has-landed/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 17:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>All good things...</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/all-good-things/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As they say, all good things must come to an end. However no matter how
much you expect the inevitable, it's still a bit of a downer when it
does happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://osafoundation.org"&gt;Open Source Applications Foundation&lt;/a&gt; has
been sponsoring my work on wxPython for about 5 years now. I spend about
half of my time working on &lt;a href="http://chandlerproject.org"&gt;Chandler&lt;/a&gt;,
supporting the other OSAF engineers with wxPython questions or problems,
or in working on specific needs that OSAF has in wxWidgets or wxPython
itself. I'm free to spend the other half of my time working on wxWidgets
or wxPython in whatever way I want. Typically I use a big chunk of this
time supporting the wxPython community, answering questions on the mail
lists, tracking down bugs that people report, etc. but I also work on
other features or long-term goals for wxPython that may not necessarily
line up with some immediate need that Chandler has. It's been a real
good deal for everybody involved. I've been able to get paid for working
on my favorite hobby, the Chandler project has gotten the support and
expertise that they needed, the wxPython community has also had a large
block of my time and attention, and wxPython itself has had many
improvements and enhancements that I likely would not have had time for
otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week OSAF
&lt;a href="http://blog.chandlerproject.org/2008/01/08/osaf-transitions/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;
a restructuring and downsizing of the Chandler team. They want to shift
the focus more towards gaining more users and, since it is an Open
Source project, the building up of a volunteer developer community. The
other goal behind the transition is a desire to stretch out the
remaining funding until the project can find a way to become
self-sustaining. As you've probably guessed by now, I was not one of the
worker bees kept in the hive. I've got a few weeks left on my contract
and then I'll be making my own transition to something else. Although
I've known this was coming, I didn't expect it until the end of this
year, so it's still a bit of a disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for wxPython? Hopefully nothing, other than some
reduction in the time I am able to spend focused on wxPython. It would
be great to be able to find someone willing to support my working &lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt;
wxPython part time like OSAF did, but it's probably pretty unlikely that
that particular lightning will strike in the same place twice. On the
other hand, I expect that my next gig will be something that at least
&lt;strong&gt;uses&lt;/strong&gt; wxPython so there will be some opportunities for some of that
work to roll down to wxPython and the community. Of course, on the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gripping_hand"&gt;gripping hand&lt;/a&gt;, if you or
somebody you know would be interested in sponsoring at least part-time
work on wxPython, please do contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="naturalfireworks.jpg" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2008/01/naturalfireworks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: This news was noticed by the 
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/idg/IDG_002570DE00740E18002573CC004F945F.html?ref=technology"&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/all-good-things/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 11:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>So maybe it's not a fad afterall...</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/so-maybe-its-not-a-fad-afterall/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I realized that this whole "blogging thing" wasn't just
a passing fad, and decided that maybe I should jump on the bandwagon and
do a bit of blogging myself. After all, within certain communities I'm a
fairly well known Internet personality, the de-facto leader of one of
those communities, and involved in several others to varying levels. So
why shouldn't I blog?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward three years... Looking back I see a series of Life Events™,
tons of work, and plenty of excuses that have gotten in the way to
actually moving forward with this project. However a few days ago a
family member asked me to set up a blog for them on my site, and I
decided that I couldn't make excuses to myself any longer and that it is
past time that I do one for myself. So I set this up at the same time as
the other blog and here it is. Now I have a place to write about 
&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/pages/about-42/"&gt;Life, the Universe, and Everything&lt;/a&gt;, and
anything else that tickles my fancy from time to time. Hopefully you'll
enjoy reading as much as I hope to enjoy writing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Life</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/so-maybe-its-not-a-fad-afterall/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 20:19:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>