<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wxPython (Posts about Quotes)</title><link>https://wxpython.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://wxpython.org/categories/quotes.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:robin@alldunn.com"&gt;The wxPython Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 03:07:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Where's my dictionary?</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/wheres-my-dictionary/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I saw this sentence today on
&lt;a href="http://arstechnica.com/news.ars/post/20080123-kde-goes-cross-platform-with-windows-mac-os-x-support.html"&gt;ArsTechnica&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"...Autotools, an intractably arcane and grotesquely anachronistic
cesspool of ineffable complexity that makes even seasoned programmers
nauseous."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that sentence could win an award if there was a
most-big-words-used-where-small-words-would-do-fine contest. Good thing
that my dictionary is only a
&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/300.html#spotlight"&gt;Spotlight&lt;/a&gt;
search away... [type][type][type]... Ah so that's what it means. Yes, I
agree. &lt;span class="emoji"&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Quotes</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/wheres-my-dictionary/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 12:52:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Po-tay-toe, Po-tah-toe</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/po-tay-toe-po-tah-toe/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week on
&lt;a href="http://news.gmane.org/gmane.comp.python.wxpython"&gt;wxPython-users&lt;/a&gt; a
user wrote about a particular GUI class and said that, "it looks really
awful." Trying to get more details from the person about what is so bad
about it only resulted in some confusion because he seems to really like
the class and listed some nice features when asked, "in what way is it
awful?" Well, as you can probably guess, it turns out that English is
not his native language and he intended to say that the GUI class in
question &lt;em&gt;filled&lt;/em&gt; him with &lt;em&gt;awe&lt;/em&gt;, or in other words, that it is "really
awesome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got me to thinking about something that has probably crossed every
computer scientist's mind at one time or another: It's too bad that our
spoken and written word can't be passed through something like a syntax
check, preprocessor, lint, or a compiler. Just think how many problems
could be caught before the communications arrived at the listener's
auditory or visual interface! If we could communicate person to person
using something that is as clean and as structured as a programming
language like &lt;a href="http://python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; then I think that there would
be a lot less confusion in the world. If our spoken word would fail to
compile if it is incorrectly spoken, and if it failed to run if the
assumptions it was built upon were incorrect, or were not fully
specified then when what is spoken does successfully execute then there
would be a much higher level of comprehension at the receiving end, and
a high level of trust that what was received was exactly what was
intended to be said. Using a structured communication mechanism like a
programming language would also allow for clear and unambiguous
responses or acknowledgments that what was said was received by the
listener, and understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would still be bugs of course, since nobody is perfect. But I
expect that if you look at the number of times that what you speak or
write is misunderstood or misinterpreted, or even just ignored, and
compare that to the number of bugs in your software that have made it
out to the customers, then I think that for almost all of us there would
be a huge difference in those numbers. So what do you think, can Python
4000 be a spoken language?&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Quotes</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/po-tay-toe-po-tah-toe/index.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2007 19:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>As seen in wxPython-users...</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/as-seen-in-wxpython-users/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I got a good chuckle out of this quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I understand that you want this. I am advising you against wanting
it." -- Chris Mellon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Quotes</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/as-seen-in-wxpython-users/index.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 16:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>