<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wxPython (Posts about Work)</title><link>https://wxpython.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://wxpython.org/categories/work.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:robin@alldunn.com"&gt;The wxPython Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 03:07:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>New Horizons</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the past few months I have been working for
&lt;a href="http://enthought.com"&gt;Enthought&lt;/a&gt; and helping out with a new upcoming
product. Since that is about to transition to a more long term
employment opportunity for me I figured it would be a good idea to let
the &lt;a href="http://wxPython.org"&gt;wxPython&lt;/a&gt; community know about it, and also to
let you know about some aspects of the job that some may find a little
surprising, before you hear about it as rumors or gossip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Software</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/new-horizons/index.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>This is really cool (Brr!)</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/this-is-really-cool-brr/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I found out last week at the &lt;a href="http://en.oreilly.com/oscon2008/"&gt;OSCON&lt;/a&gt;
conference that my software is being used at the South Pole by the
&lt;a href="http://icecube.wisc.edu/"&gt;IceCube Neutrino Observatory&lt;/a&gt; project
currently being constructed about a kilometer from the Pole.  They are
using &lt;a href="http://wxPython.org/"&gt;wxPython&lt;/a&gt; for the controller user interface
of the &lt;a href="http://gallery.icecube.wisc.edu/external/3-build-ehwd/"&gt;machine&lt;/a&gt;
that is drilling holes 2.4 kilometers down into the ice.  There isn't
anything on their website about that piece of software, but it's real
interesting anyway ;-) 
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SskyDuTfH0o"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is a bit more about
the drill.  There are also these
&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ksbeattie/sets/72157594267166135/"&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/view_play_list?p=51EF4CAB8762D855"&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://ksblog.wordpress.com/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; from one of the scientists that
gave the presentation I attended where he shows a bit about what life at
the Pole is like.  (Where a nice warm summer's day might get up to -31F.
Brr!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This news means that I now have reports of wxPython being used from
every continent on this planet. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>General</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/this-is-really-cool-brr/index.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 19:07:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>"Tranquility base here, the Robin has landed..."</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/tranquility-base-here-the-robin-has-landed/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Since a number of folks have expressed interest and concern I thought I
would give a quick update on my working situation. This week I've
started a full-time consulting job with a small software group at the
&lt;a href="http://unmc.edu"&gt;University of Nebraska Medical Center&lt;/a&gt;. If you
attended &lt;a href="http://pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; a couple years ago then you may have
seen their
&lt;a href="http://us.pycon.org/zope/talks/2006/sun/track1/37/talkDetails"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;
about IntúaCare and IntúaDesign. That is the project that I'll be
working with. I'll be working &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; wxPython a lot, and probably also
working &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; wxWidgets and wxPython to some extent as well, although not
as much as I did with OSAF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm excited to be working on this project. Not just because of wxPython,
but also because I have previous experience with the subject matter. My
first major job out of college was working on software products that had
a lot of the same goals as the IntúaSolutions products: essentially to
be a highly dynamic and flexible solution for collecting and reporting
medical patient care data in hospitals. The key here is the "highly
dynamic and flexible" part, the intent is to have a set of
domain-specific tools where unskilled (a.k.a non-programmers) but
knowledgeable people can easily tailor the application to the needs of
each hospital, or even each department within the hospital. My former
experience with this was back in the dark days of DOS so the products
had only a textual user interface, but I think we managed to accomplish
a lot with it and it was a very successful product line, and at least as
of a few years ago it was still going strong, although they've
modernized a bunch of things since I worked there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously a few things have changed in the computer world since then. I
discovered Python a year or so after I left that job and I've always
wondered what it would have been like if we had used Python as the
internal macro/calculation/filtering/query language instead of our
home-grown RDL (for anyone outside of the marketing group and the
customers that acronym stands for Robin Dunn's Language, otherwise it is
Rule Definition Language.) Since that time we've also gone through the
rise of the graphical user interface, the explosion of the World Wide
Web, and my current notebook computer has 7.5 times the number of pixels
on screen and 8 times more RAM than the hard drive space in the brand
new top of the line desktop computer I had when we started that project!
It should be fun to be able to apply modern technology and my new skills
to similar features and issues that I dealt with 14-18 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've linked to this video as a way to let you know how big of an effort
this job search seemed to be at times, and also how good it felt when it
was finally complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;object height="355" width="425"&gt;
&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/xLu0Ak9Blog&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;&lt;param name="wmode" value="transparent"&gt;

&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/xLu0Ak9Blog&amp;amp;hl=en" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" height="355" width="425"&gt;
&lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/tranquility-base-here-the-robin-has-landed/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 17:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>All good things...</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/all-good-things/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;As they say, all good things must come to an end. However no matter how
much you expect the inevitable, it's still a bit of a downer when it
does happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://osafoundation.org"&gt;Open Source Applications Foundation&lt;/a&gt; has
been sponsoring my work on wxPython for about 5 years now. I spend about
half of my time working on &lt;a href="http://chandlerproject.org"&gt;Chandler&lt;/a&gt;,
supporting the other OSAF engineers with wxPython questions or problems,
or in working on specific needs that OSAF has in wxWidgets or wxPython
itself. I'm free to spend the other half of my time working on wxWidgets
or wxPython in whatever way I want. Typically I use a big chunk of this
time supporting the wxPython community, answering questions on the mail
lists, tracking down bugs that people report, etc. but I also work on
other features or long-term goals for wxPython that may not necessarily
line up with some immediate need that Chandler has. It's been a real
good deal for everybody involved. I've been able to get paid for working
on my favorite hobby, the Chandler project has gotten the support and
expertise that they needed, the wxPython community has also had a large
block of my time and attention, and wxPython itself has had many
improvements and enhancements that I likely would not have had time for
otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week OSAF
&lt;a href="http://blog.chandlerproject.org/2008/01/08/osaf-transitions/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;
a restructuring and downsizing of the Chandler team. They want to shift
the focus more towards gaining more users and, since it is an Open
Source project, the building up of a volunteer developer community. The
other goal behind the transition is a desire to stretch out the
remaining funding until the project can find a way to become
self-sustaining. As you've probably guessed by now, I was not one of the
worker bees kept in the hive. I've got a few weeks left on my contract
and then I'll be making my own transition to something else. Although
I've known this was coming, I didn't expect it until the end of this
year, so it's still a bit of a disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean for wxPython? Hopefully nothing, other than some
reduction in the time I am able to spend focused on wxPython. It would
be great to be able to find someone willing to support my working &lt;strong&gt;on&lt;/strong&gt;
wxPython part time like OSAF did, but it's probably pretty unlikely that
that particular lightning will strike in the same place twice. On the
other hand, I expect that my next gig will be something that at least
&lt;strong&gt;uses&lt;/strong&gt; wxPython so there will be some opportunities for some of that
work to roll down to wxPython and the community. Of course, on the
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gripping_hand"&gt;gripping hand&lt;/a&gt;, if you or
somebody you know would be interested in sponsoring at least part-time
work on wxPython, please do contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="naturalfireworks.jpg" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2008/01/naturalfireworks.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: This news was noticed by the 
&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/idg/IDG_002570DE00740E18002573CC004F945F.html?ref=technology"&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Life</category><category>Work</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/all-good-things/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2008 11:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>