<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wxPython (Posts about Linux)</title><link>https://wxpython.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://wxpython.org/categories/linux.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2025 &lt;a href="mailto:robin@alldunn.com"&gt;The wxPython Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 04:33:37 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Linux Build Post Updated</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/2018-02-03-linux-build-info-updated/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post to let everyone know that the previous post in this blog,
&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/blog/2017-08-17-builds-for-linux-with-pip/index.html"&gt;Building wxPython for Linux via Pip&lt;/a&gt;
has been updated to include a simple set of build steps detailing how you can build your
own wxPython wheel on Linux or other Unix-like systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>Build</category><category>Linux</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/2018-02-03-linux-build-info-updated/index.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 22:06:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Building wxPython for Linux via Pip</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/2017-08-17-builds-for-linux-with-pip/index.html</link><dc:creator>Mesalu and Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ Post updated 2018-02-03, see new &lt;strong&gt;Build Steps&lt;/strong&gt; section below. ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;wxPython Wheels for Linux?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before reading further, you may want to check and see if there are already
some wxPython wheels available for your flavor of Linux. A few are built as
part of the release process and are available from one of wxPython's
servers. More details and some links are on the 
&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/pages/downloads/"&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are no existing wheels there for your distro, (or perhaps a close
relative,) then read on to find out why we can't just provide wheels for
all Linuxes, and what you need to build one for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Problem&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been some issues flowing into Phoenix's issue tracker since the
release of wxPython 4.0.0b1 related to installation issues on Linux using
pip, which have caused some overhead and soaked up unnecessary amounts of
time. So lets start with getting some of the basics out of the way. There
are a lot of flavors of linux. To name a few there's the Debian family,
Debian, Ubuntu, Kubuntu, Elementary, Mint, etc., Arch, Gentoo, RHEL and CentOS,
and so on. Each flavor has differences which can make binary distributions
incompatible across flavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does this affect wxPython you may ask? It's just a Python package, and
Python source is independent across operating systems after all, right?.
Well, not all Python packages are just Python. wxPython as an example
contains binary extension modules (compiled C or C++ code that is platform
and architecture dependent.)  wxPython by default also contains a copy of
the compiled version of the wxWidgets library written in C++, which also
depends on other 3rd party libraries which need to not only be present at
runtime, but also have their development-related files present at
wxWidgets' and wxPython's compile time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pip in its infinite wisdom can detect this, and knows how to select the
appropriate binary wheel for the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS (Windows, macOS, Linux)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture (i386, x86_64, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python Version (2.7, 3.5, 3.6, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See how pip doesn't care about the specific linux distribution? That's the
issue. The binary content and dependencies of wxPython can't be delivered
consistently via pip. There are some efforts to get around this (eg.  &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0513/"&gt;PEP
513&lt;/a&gt; a.k.a. &lt;code&gt;manylinux1&lt;/code&gt;) but
they don't quite work for wxPython yet. Packages that are able to fit into
the very narrow &lt;code&gt;manylinux1&lt;/code&gt; requirements can be hosted on PyPI and will
install with pip just as smoothly as pure-python packages do. Unfortunately
the &lt;code&gt;manylinux1&lt;/code&gt; spec does not include a version of GTK+ and its
dependencies that are new enough to be able to provide all the features
that wxWidgets requires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to deploy to linux systems wxPython4 (Phoenix) simply builds
itself from a source tarball as part of the pip setup process. All of the
code generated by wxPython's build system is already present in the
tarball, it merely needs to be compiled. This causes a very lengthy
installation times, but is a necessary evil. Because the build is just
that, a build, you will need all of wxWidgets and wxPython's binary
dependencies present at build time. wxWidgets' configure will be run, and
if it detects missing libraries the whole build, and therefore the pip
installation, will fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What You Need&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need the following packages (please consult your distribution's
package list for the appropriate package names) and their dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python-dev (for your version of python)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gtk (preferably version 3, but depends on your needs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gstreamer &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gstreamer-plugins-base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;glut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libwebkitgtk (matching your gtk version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libjpeg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libpng&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libtiff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libsdl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libnotify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;libsm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;on Debian based systems, or other systems that separate development
packages from standard packages, you will need the corresponding &lt;code&gt;-dev&lt;/code&gt; or
&lt;code&gt;-devel&lt;/code&gt; package in addition to the standard package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the appropriate packages are present on your system then wxPython
should build with no problems, either with pip or from a source tree
extracted from the source tarball. If it still doesn't work for you then be
sure to look closely at the build log as there will likely be some clues
there that may point you in the right direction.  For example, this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;checking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;OpenGL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;... &lt;span class="nv"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;found&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;checking&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;GL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;gl&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="nv"&gt;h&lt;/span&gt;... &lt;span class="nv"&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;configure&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class="nv"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class="nv"&gt;OpenGL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;libraries&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;available&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;will tell you that the OpenGL libraries are missing. They are usually a
dependency of the glut or freeglut packages and should have been installed
along with that library, but perhaps your system's dependencies are
different and you'll need to do a little investigation to determine the
proper system packages that need to be installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Build Steps&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have installed the required depenency libraries, it should take
just a few steps to build a wxPython that will work on your system with
your Python. The steps shown here are just one option, but seems to be one
of the simpler approaches to take, and will require nothing extra to be
installed in your system Python. These instructions assume that you will be
using a 3.4+ version of Python and that the executable is called "python3".
If you are using 2.7 or the binary is called something else then adapt
accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; The first thing we'll do is create and activate a new virtual
environment for the build and the initial testing. This is optional, but
highly recommended as it will ensure that there is nothing left over from a
previous build that could trip things up. The last two commands shown here
are just so you can verify that the python and pip commands are now being
found in the new virtual environment instead of from the system or other
Python environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [some tmp folder]

python3 -m venv builder_py
source builder_py/bin/activate

which python
which pip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Next, you'll want to update pip and add a few more packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;U&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;pip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;install&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;U&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;six&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;wheel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;setuptools&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Use pip to download the latest source archive from PyPI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;download&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;wxPython&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Use pip to build a wxPython wheel file. We'll also redirect the
build output to a file so you can review it later if needed. This step will
take a while to complete, as it will be compiling all the wxWidgets and
wxPython source code, but you'll be able to watch the build output to
monitor the progress. Be sure to use the actual name of the downloaded
source archive file, which may be different than the one shown here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip wheel -v wxPython-4.0.1.tar.gz  2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1 | tee build.log
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 5:&lt;/strong&gt; If the build was successful then you should now have a wxPython
wheel file in the current working directory. If there was a problem then
review the &lt;code&gt;build.log&lt;/code&gt; file and see if you can spot any clues as to what
dependencies may be missing or out of date. (Build problems from wxPython
release sources are almost always due to missing dependencies.) Once you
think you have solved the problem go back to step 4 and try the build
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 6:&lt;/strong&gt; The next step is to install the wheel file in the virtual
environment and give it a quick test run. (Use the actual name of the wheel
file you built, which may be different than the one shown here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code literal-block"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pip&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;wxPython&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;4.0.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cp35&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cp35m&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;linux_x86_64&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;whl&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;c&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;"import wx; a=wx.App(); wx.Frame(None,title='hello world').Show(); a.MainLoop();"&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see a new window open with a "hello world" title bar, which will
indicate that this build was successful and this wxPython wheel can be used
on your system. You can now use pip to install the wheel file in other
Python environments or virtual environments that use the same base Python
executable that you used for this build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;wxPython's build tools on Linux assume that the Python being used was configured
with the &lt;code&gt;--enable-shared&lt;/code&gt; flag. That is usually true for Pythons installed from
the Linux distro's repositories, as well as for most known 3rd Party Python
distributions for Linux. However, that flag is not enabled by default. So if
your Python is one that you've configured and built yourself, then double-check
that you used the flag. If it wasn't then you'll likely see a configuration
error when the build gets to the wxPython portion (after it has built
wxWidgets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv"&gt;pyenv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; does not use the
&lt;code&gt;--enable-shared&lt;/code&gt; flag when it builds a Python environment for you. 
There is a note in the 
&lt;a href="https://github.com/pyenv/pyenv/wiki#how-to-build-cpython-with---enable-shared"&gt;pyenv wiki&lt;/a&gt; 
that shows how to add the flag when it builds a new Python environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;FAQ&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q1: "Why can't you just install the necessary packages as part of
wxPython's installation"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A1: Lots of good reasons, among them are: Pip is NOT your linux package
manager, Phoenix is not responsible for maintaining your system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q2: "I can install PyQt(4/5) just fine via pip! Why can't wxPython do the
same?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A2: Qt does not depend on system provided libraries other than the low-
level basic libs. wxWidgets does, it's one of the defining differences of
the two toolkits. As such PyQt can deliver to all linuxes in the same
manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Build</category><category>Linux</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/2017-08-17-builds-for-linux-with-pip/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 19:14:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Whyteboard gets noticed</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/whyteboard-gets-noticed/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wxpython.org/images/2010/06/wbpdf.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2010/06/wbpdf-300x240.png" title="Whyteboard"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://whyteboard.org/"&gt;Whyteboard&lt;/a&gt;, a useful application written using
wxPython for the GUI, was just
&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/blog/whyteboard-aids-in-teachable-moments/"&gt;noticed&lt;/a&gt;
over at SourceForge.  Congrats Sproaty!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Development</category><category>Linux</category><category>Mac</category><category>Software</category><category>Windows</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/whyteboard-gets-noticed/index.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 09:03:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Time to kick myself again</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/time-to-kick-myself-again/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever have one of those moments when you see some product or service and
you think, "&lt;em&gt;Doh! I should have thought of that!&lt;/em&gt;" because it is
something that makes so much sense to you that you can't believe that
you hadn't invented it yourself long before?  Well I had one of those
moments today with &lt;a href="https://www.getdropbox.com/"&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;.  Dropbox is a
cool service that integrates versioned shared storage on a centralized
server with your Mac, Windows or Linux desktops.  Syncronizing files
between your computers, whereever they are located, is as simple as
dragging the files into your dropbox.  New or changed files are
automatically replicated to your dropbox on the other computers.  If
existing files are changed then only the deltas are transported across
the wire, in a rsync-like fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the simple file sharing among your own computers, there are some
other nice features there too.  Files are private by default, but there
is a Public folder where you can put files you want to share with
others, and you can easily get a public URL for them to paste into
emails or IM messages.  You can also create a shared folder that you
share with other Dropbox users.  Any changes you make in your shared
folder are instantly updated to the other users' copy of the shared
folder, and their changes are replicated back to you. In addition to all
of that, you can easily get back to prior versions of changed files, and
you can undelete files that have been deleted.  And as if that wasn't
enough, there is another special folder type that is an automatic photo
gallery, you just need to drag the photos you want to share to a Photos
folder and the rest is automatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get 2GB of space for free, and you can get up to 50GB for $10 per
month or $99 per year.  If you sign up with this &lt;a href="https://www.getdropbox.com/referrals/NTcyNzI1NTk"&gt;referal
link&lt;/a&gt; then you and I
will both get an extra 250MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, here is the real kicker:  The Dropbox user interface (setup
wizard, preferences dialog, task bar icon, etc.) is written in
wxPython!  If the user ID I saw when I signed up is related in some way
to the number of users (it is just a number so that may be possible)
then that means that there are about three quarters of a million users
running a wxPython application on their computers and they may not even
know it.  Good job guys, I'm impressed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="snap002.png" src="https://wxpython.org/images/2009/03/snap002.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Linux</category><category>Mac</category><category>TooCool</category><category>Windows</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/time-to-kick-myself-again/index.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 19:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>One month with Mac</title><link>https://wxpython.org/blog/one-month-with-mac/index.html</link><dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been about a month since I switched my primary computer to a
&lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/macbookpro/"&gt;MacBook Pro&lt;/a&gt;, (2.4 GHz, 4G ram, with
the new 17 inch hi-rez display) which I got for myself for my birthday.
So I thought that this would be a good time for a review, and since I'm
now a blogger it makes sense to share it with all of you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First a little background and why I decided to switch. For the past four
or five years I've been using a &lt;a href="http://www.dell.com"&gt;Dell&lt;/a&gt; Inspiron
8200 laptop running Linux as my primary machine. By "primary machine" I
mean the one where I do most of my development work, web browsing,
email, word processing and etc. I also have a few other computers on and
under my desk which are used for developing and testing
&lt;a href="http://wxPython.org/"&gt;wxPython&lt;/a&gt; on the various platforms I support,
creating the binaries that I distribute, as well as some platform
specific tasks. I was real happy using Linux as my primary desktop,
especially for the last year and a half since I switched to
&lt;a href="http://www.ubuntu.com/"&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;. Almost everything I needed or wanted
from my desktop system was available in one way or another, as well as
plenty of things to satisfy my inner geek. However there were a few key
things that prompted me to switch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even with the fantastic hardware support that Ubuntu has, I still
    had troubles with wireless networking, especially when trying to
    access a WEP protected network, and also troubles with suspending
    the laptop. Every time I suspended I had to cross my fingers and
    hope that it would come back in one piece. Even if it did restore, I
    usually had to restart some services, and it often would not
    suspend/resume more than a few times without needing a reboot. I
    knew that using an Apple notebook computer and OS X instead would
    give me excellent hardware support in these areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever since the advent of &lt;a href="http://www.vmware.com"&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; I've used
    it to help me in my work, although after the Dell got to be a few
    years old it didn't feel fast enough to depend on it as a VMware
    host very much, especially since I had all these other computers on
    my desk running at native speeds. Also, since Apple doesn't allow OS
    X to be used in a virtual machine it wasn't much help there. However
    with a fast Mac with enough memory I could easily use it as VM host
    and run Windows and Linux VM guests on it, allowing me to have all
    the platforms I need for my work all wrapped up in nice a portable
    package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although there has been a lot of hype over the years about the
    premium you have to pay to have Apple hardware, I don't think that
    is very true anymore once you consider the quality of the hardware.
    Sure, you can get cheapo PCs and not have to lay out very much cash
    for them, but you pay for it down the road with upgrades and
    hardware failures. Once you start comparing high end, high quality
    hardware with good support, PCs and Apples cost about the same. I
    did a price comparison with Dell, choosing what I would get if I
    were to replace my old Dell with the new one, and it actually priced
    out at a couple hundred more than what I paid for the MacBook Pro.
    Of course that includes the Microsoft Tax which would have been
    wasted on that machine for me because I would have installed Linux
    on it first thing. (And getting Linux from Dell wouldn't have been
    an option because they don't offer it on the machine I would have
    bought from them.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all the transition went a lot smoother than I expected. I've used
Mac OS X for software development related tasks for a number of years
now, but I had never really investigated what it would take for it to be
my day-to-day machine. I knew my way around the file-system, using some
of the applications that Apple ships with OS X, and a few of the Free
and Open Source development related tools that I had installed, and also
using the compiler and debugger, but that was about it. I was worried
that there were too many things that I would miss from Linux, or that
would be too difficult for me to get used to, or that something would go
wrong, or that it would take too long to make the transition and that my
work would suffer. But it just hasn't been the case. I had the old Dell
and the new MacBook sitting side by side for a few days while I moved
things over, and set up the new software, but I expected to need to do
that for a week or two. One day I surprised myself when I realized that
I hadn't even turned on the Dell for several days and that my setup
tasks were way ahead of schedule. The hardest thing I dealt with was
trying to decide which IRC client to go with. (I finally settled on
&lt;a href="http://colloquy.info/"&gt;Colloquy&lt;/a&gt;, but &lt;a href="http://linkinus.com/"&gt;Linkinus&lt;/a&gt;
was a close second.) Every time I went to look for some software to fill
a need for something I used regularly on the old machine, I was able to
find something that was either Free/Open Source or that was inexpensive
shareware. The only commercial software that I've bought so far is
VMware, but I expect to get one or two others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now the Dell has had its original Windows XP reinstalled and it has
been recycled into being the first laptop for a member of my family.
I've been using the Mac almost exclusively for a few weeks now, and it
has been great. There are a few things that I don't like, or at least
haven't adjusted to yet and it hasn't been quite as stable as I expected
(more about these in another article) but all in all I've been very
pleased with my choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three main bullet points above have been satisfied very well. I've
had no issues with networking at all, and it seamlessly transitions from
wired to wireless and back with no interruptions in service. I've even
had ssh sessions that remained connected when the wireless dropped for
several minutes, and I was able to pick up where I left off when the
wireless link came back again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleeping and resuming works wonderfully, with no crossed fingers
required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion/"&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt; has been a
dream come true. Its support for Windows guests is not quite as polished
as Parallels, (but it's only a 1.0 product so I expect that to improve
over time,) and it's support for Linux guests far out-shines that of
Parallels. There are a few features I miss from the VMware Workstation
product available for other platforms, but they are not that critical
for day to day operation. I'm able to have two "large" VMs running
simultaneously and the computer doesn't even break a sweat. For CPU and
disk intensive things like compiles the Linux virtual machine is
actually much faster than doing the same thing directly on the Dell
hardware was, although it's not as fast as running it on Cyclops, which
happens to have the same CPU as the MacBook. (Cyclops is one of the
Linux PCs under my desk which is used for making the wxPython binary
packages for Linux) The Windows VM is also almost as fast for
development work as the Windows PC I was using before. I still have that
PC running because it is doing other things for me, but I've moved my
development work to the VM because of the convenience factor.
Incidentally, I can have compiles running in both VMs, and still be
using the host machine's applications without noticing any slowdowns or
jerkiness in their UI at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I've rambled on long enough for one article. I've not yet covered
all the things I thought I would in this post so I expect I'll make a
few more on this subject over the next few weeks. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Hardware</category><category>Linux</category><category>Mac</category><guid>https://wxpython.org/blog/one-month-with-mac/index.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 01:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>